<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Swim England North East</title>
	<atom:link href="https://asaner.org.uk/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>https://asaner.org.uk</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2019 15:12:15 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-GB</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	
	<item>
		<title>National Para Swimming Championships</title>
		<link>https://asaner.org.uk/national-para-swimming-championships-2/</link>
				<pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2019 15:08:42 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Small]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Disability Swimming]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://asaner.org.uk/?p=20162</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<p>Well done to the swimmers, coaches and volunteers from the Swim England North East Region who were involved in the National Para Swimming Championships held in Manchester over the weekend. A full review of the event and the race results are available by clicking here: 2019 results. &#160;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asaner.org.uk/national-para-swimming-championships-2/">National Para Swimming Championships</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asaner.org.uk">Swim England North East</a>.</p>
]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Well done to the swimmers, coaches and volunteers from the Swim England North East Region who were involved in the National Para Swimming Championships held in Manchester over the weekend.</p>
<p>A full review of the event and the race results are available by clicking here: <a href="https://www.swimmingresults.org.uk/disability/results/2019/aalc/">2019 results</a>.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asaner.org.uk/national-para-swimming-championships-2/">National Para Swimming Championships</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asaner.org.uk">Swim England North East</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Gold’s for City of Sheffield’s Maisie Bond at Camo Invitational Diving Competition</title>
		<link>https://asaner.org.uk/golds-for-city-of-sheffields-maisie-bond-at-camo-invitational-diving-competition/</link>
				<pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2019 14:01:38 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Small]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Diving]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://asaner.org.uk/?p=20157</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<p>Over the past couple of days, Swim England divers have been enjoying success at the Camo Invitational in Canada. On the first day of the competition, City of Sheffield’s Maisie Bond set a new personal best as she joined Crystal Palace’s Jack Jefford on top of the podium at the Claude Robillard Sports Complex, in [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asaner.org.uk/golds-for-city-of-sheffields-maisie-bond-at-camo-invitational-diving-competition/">Gold’s for City of Sheffield’s Maisie Bond at Camo Invitational Diving Competition</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asaner.org.uk">Swim England North East</a>.</p>
]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Over the past couple of days, Swim England divers have been enjoying success at the Camo Invitational in Canada.</p>
<p>On the first day of the competition, City of Sheffield’s Maisie Bond set a new personal best as she joined Crystal Palace’s Jack Jefford on top of the podium at the Claude Robillard Sports Complex, in Montreal.</p>
<p>Maise was 35.25 points ahead of second-placed Heloa Camelo, of Brazil, after scoring an impressive 283.95 in the Girls’ C 1m Springboard. Her team mate, Jenna Davison was 19th in the preliminary round and missed out on a place in the final.</p>
<p>Suzie Collins, Swim England Talent Development Officer Diving, said: <em>“It’s been a great opening day for the team and fantastic to hear the national anthem ringing around the Claude Robillard Sports Complex twice.</em></p>
<p><em>We’re really settled in now and looking forward to getting the Group Bs on the platform.”</em></p>
<p>On the second day of competition, Masie was once again on the top of the podium, leading from start to finish in the Girls’ C Platform competition, saving her best dive until last.</p>
<p>Her back two-and-a-half somersaults tucked from the 7m board earned her nines and ensured she smashed through the 300-point mark.</p>
<p>Maisie’s total of 305.25 was 42.45 points ahead of Germany’s Lena Philin Schneider, who took the silver medal while Jenna Davison was sixth on 298.60.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asaner.org.uk/golds-for-city-of-sheffields-maisie-bond-at-camo-invitational-diving-competition/">Gold’s for City of Sheffield’s Maisie Bond at Camo Invitational Diving Competition</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asaner.org.uk">Swim England North East</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>North East Region U14 Girls Water Polo Team &#8211; Swim England Inter-Regional Champions 2019</title>
		<link>https://asaner.org.uk/u14-girls-water-polo-team-swim-england-inter-regional-champions-2019/</link>
				<pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2019 10:33:27 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[David Parry]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Clubs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Water Polo]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://asaner.org.uk/?p=20141</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<p>The North East 2006+ Girls team competed at the Inter Regions in Walsall on 30th November and the 1st Dec 2020. The team’s Head Coach, Kevin Swainson, reports: “We had our team talk before the first match and set out our tactics for the weekend.  I felt that if we played as a team, not [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asaner.org.uk/u14-girls-water-polo-team-swim-england-inter-regional-champions-2019/">North East Region U14 Girls Water Polo Team &#8211; Swim England Inter-Regional Champions 2019</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asaner.org.uk">Swim England North East</a>.</p>
]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The North East 2006+ Girls team competed at the Inter Regions in Walsall on 30th November and the 1<sup>st</sup> Dec 2020.</p>
<p>The team’s Head Coach, Kevin Swainson, reports:</p>
<p><em>“We had our team talk before the first match and set out our tactics for the weekend.  I felt that if we played as a team, not as individuals, we had a very good chance of a medal.</em></p>
<p><em>Going into the competition I was confident in our team, with two very capable Centre Backs in Connie and Amelia I felt that we could ball line press in defence and put allot of pressure on the attacking team. We had worked hard on this in the last few weeks and it paid dividends at the weekend only conceding 17 goals in the whole tournament and causing the attacking teams allot of problems. </em></p>
<p><em>This was complimented by our scoring capabilities; we played excellent as a team in attack with very good, unselfish water polo from the whole team resulting in every single player scoring during the weekend.   This included taking advantage of the new rules and allowing our</em> <em>goalkeeper to join the attack.  Severn came out to attack three times and we scored on all three occasions including two goals from our goalkeeper Severn which I think was one of the highlights of the whole weekend for the whole team. We managed 75 goals in 6 matches, that is 17 more than any other team in the competition.</em></p>
<p><em>The semi-final against North West was a fantastic match and in fairness the score did not reflect how close the match was, the girls started fantastic against the tournaments number one seed and showed grit and determination for the full match.</em></p>
<p><em>The final was a re-match of our earlier encounter with Ireland, Ireland had won the first time 7-4 but we felt that this could be a result that we could turn around.  Ireland came at us very strong, frustrating our players in attack and forcing us to rush and make mistakes.  With the score line at 5-2 down with only 3 minutes left on the clock some teams would have given up but the girls showed grit, determination and heart to score 3 times in the last 3 mins to take the match to penalties.</em></p>
<p><em>No one likes a penalty shootout but the girls although extremely nervous performed fantastic, good penalties taken by all the players and Severn managing to pull off two fantastic saves won us the title.</em></p>
<p><em>Congratulations to Laura who won team MVP, Tournament MVP and top goal scorer in the tournament.</em></p>
<p><em>Special thanks to Gabby, Liz and Michelle for your help at the weekend and for your assistance in the weeks building up to the competition.</em></p>
<p><em>Thank you to the parents for your support during the weekend, without your support we would not be the team we are.</em></p>
<p><em>And last but probably the most important, thank you to the players for the effort you all put it to make this weekend such a success and so enjoyable.  The team not only worked well together in the pool they all got on so well outside the pool and on behalf of myself, gabby and Liz I would like to wish the team a long and successful future in the sport.&#8221;</em></p>
<p>The Team included:</p>
<p>Severn Annakin &#8211; St bede&#8217;s and st joseph&#8217;s catholic college<br />
Amelia Hendesron &#8211; Sedgefield WPC<br />
Ruby Taylor &#8211; City of Sheffield WPC<br />
Connie Swainson &#8211; Rotherham Metro WPC<br />
Lilly Pryce &#8211; St bede&#8217;s and st joseph&#8217;s catholic college<br />
Lola Carver-Brown &#8211; Rotherham Metro<br />
Caitlin Urqhuart &#8211; City of Sheffield WPC<br />
Laura Skelton &#8211; Rotherham Metro<br />
Amelia Brooksbank &#8211; St bede&#8217;s and st joseph&#8217;s catholic college<br />
Isobel Olcer &#8211; Rotherham Metro WPC</p>
<p><strong><u>Results</u></strong></p>
<p>North east Steelers     26 – 0 Wales</p>
<p>North east Steelers     4 – 7 Ireland</p>
<p>North east Steelers     16 – 0 East Midland</p>
<p>North east Steelers     14 – 1 South East</p>
<p><strong><u>Semi Final </u></strong></p>
<p>North east Steelers     10 – 4 North West Thunder</p>
<p><strong><u>Final</u></strong></p>
<p>North east Steelers     8 – 6 Ireland (After Penalties)</p>
<p>Well done, congratulations and thanks to all involved for your achievement.</p>
<p style="line-height: 115%; margin: 0cm 0cm 10.0pt 0cm;">
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asaner.org.uk/u14-girls-water-polo-team-swim-england-inter-regional-champions-2019/">North East Region U14 Girls Water Polo Team &#8211; Swim England Inter-Regional Champions 2019</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asaner.org.uk">Swim England North East</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Northumberland and Durham Masters Swimmers at Inter County Competition</title>
		<link>https://asaner.org.uk/northumberland-and-durham-masters-swimmers-at-inter-county-competition/</link>
				<pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2019 13:15:52 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sarah Small]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Masters Swimming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Northumberland and Durham]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://asaner.org.uk/?p=20133</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<p>On the 10th November 2019, 24 Northumberland and Durham masters swimmers travelled to Huddersfield for the masters inter counties where the Northumberland and Durham team finished in 16th position. It was a fantastic  performance by the team, with many swimmers competing in up to 10 events! There was only one event in which the team [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asaner.org.uk/northumberland-and-durham-masters-swimmers-at-inter-county-competition/">Northumberland and Durham Masters Swimmers at Inter County Competition</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asaner.org.uk">Swim England North East</a>.</p>
]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>On the 10th November 2019, 24 Northumberland and Durham masters swimmers travelled to Huddersfield for the masters inter counties where the Northumberland and Durham team finished in 16th position.</p>
<p>It was a fantastic  performance by the team, with many swimmers competing in up to 10 events! There was only one event in which the team didn&#8217;t have a swimmer, the ladies over 75.</p>
<p>The next masters competition is at the end of January 2020 in Carlisle. Full results from the competition in Huddersfield can be <a href="https://www.swimmingresults.org/mastersdata/results/2019/191110InterCountyResults.pdf?fbclid=IwAR0zif1VX1u0aQhDAiAgLjtCS4QWQdKBtPzz2tgoQ4_rh_ANa5hcFu29fMg">found here</a>.</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asaner.org.uk/northumberland-and-durham-masters-swimmers-at-inter-county-competition/">Northumberland and Durham Masters Swimmers at Inter County Competition</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asaner.org.uk">Swim England North East</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Honorary Fellowship for Paralympian Swimmer</title>
		<link>https://asaner.org.uk/20126-2/</link>
				<pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 15:30:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[David Parry]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Clubs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Disability Swimming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Northumberland and Durham]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://asaner.org.uk/?p=20126</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<p>Josef Craig has swapped his swimwear for a cap and gown as he received an Honorary Fellowship from the University of Sunderland during their winter Academic Awards. Full details are available by clicking here. Photo by David Wood photography</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asaner.org.uk/20126-2/">Honorary Fellowship for Paralympian Swimmer</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asaner.org.uk">Swim England North East</a>.</p>
]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Josef Craig has swapped his swimwear for a cap and gown as he received an Honorary Fellowship from the University of Sunderland during their winter Academic Awards.</p>
<p>Full details are available by <a href="https://www.bbc.co.uk/news/live/uk-england-tyne-50519516?ns_mchannel=social&amp;ns_source=twitter&amp;ns_campaign=bbc_live&amp;ns_linkname=5ddfcaf8fb9d240676c455fc%26University%20honours%20Jarrow%20golden%20boy%20Josef%262019-11-28T14%3A36%3A57.211Z&amp;ns_fee=0&amp;pinned_post_locator=urn:asset:d5ebb6f7-277d-4c77-acf2-837533c8409b&amp;pinned_post_asset_id=5ddfcaf8fb9d240676c455fc&amp;pinned_post_type=share">clicking here.</a></p>
<p>Photo by David Wood photography</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asaner.org.uk/20126-2/">Honorary Fellowship for Paralympian Swimmer</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asaner.org.uk">Swim England North East</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Easyfundraising Webinar &#8211; free funds for clubs!</title>
		<link>https://asaner.org.uk/easyfundraising-webinar-free-funds-for-clubs/</link>
				<pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 10:41:31 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[David Parry]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Clubs]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://asaner.org.uk/?p=20119</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<p>Don&#8217;t miss out on this opportunity to hear about how to get free funding for your aquatics club through everyday online shopping with 4000+ retailers including Trainline, Booking.com, Amazon, eBay, John Lewis and Partners and Sainsbury’s. Find out how to fund equipment for your club, raise funds for an event or fund coaching qualifications just [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asaner.org.uk/easyfundraising-webinar-free-funds-for-clubs/">Easyfundraising Webinar &#8211; free funds for clubs!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asaner.org.uk">Swim England North East</a>.</p>
]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Don&#8217;t miss out on this opportunity to hear about how to get free funding for your aquatics club through everyday online shopping with 4000+ retailers including Trainline, Booking.com, Amazon, eBay, John Lewis and Partners and Sainsbury’s.</p>
<p>Find out how to fund equipment for your club, raise funds for an event or fund coaching qualifications just by shopping online.</p>
<p>To help you to make the most of the scheme, Easyfundraising are hosting a short webinar where they will share:</p>
<p>* how other clubs have been successful<br />
* how you can utilise the free resources available<br />
* and some tips for fundraising success.</p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>There are three opportunities to see the webinar: Click on a date to register or Visit &#8211; <a href="https://www.easyfundraising.org.uk/swim-england-webinars">https://www.easyfundraising.org.uk/swim-england-webinars</a></p>
<p><a href="https://zoom.us/webinar/register/WN_X_xgye5FRS2FNEGEwqKF2A">5<sup>th</sup> December – 1:00pm</a>,</p>
<p><a href="https://zoom.us/webinar/register/WN_TFDL-u4eTrasYEb9hsFu8A">5<sup>th</sup> December – 7:30pm</a></p>
<p><a href="https://zoom.us/webinar/register/WN_7i9k1YxyTcqRNGTq5h0VwQ">11<sup>th</sup> December – 12:00pm</a></p>
<p>If your aquatics club isn&#8217;t yet signed up with easyfundraising, or to find out more simply visit <a href="http://www.easyfundraising.org.uk/swim-england">www.easyfundraising.org.uk/swim-england</a>  to register for your free account.</p>
<p style="font-style: italic;">Post expires at 10:37am on Friday December 6th, 2019</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asaner.org.uk/easyfundraising-webinar-free-funds-for-clubs/">Easyfundraising Webinar &#8211; free funds for clubs!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asaner.org.uk">Swim England North East</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Swim England North East Region Ltd. &#8211; 4 additional Directors vacancies</title>
		<link>https://asaner.org.uk/swim-england-north-east-region-ltd-4-additional-directors-vacancies/</link>
				<pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 10:40:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Linda Tjaguns]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Clubs]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://asaner.org.uk/?p=19926</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<p>Swim England North East Region Ltd. are now recruiting for up to 4 additional Directors to work alongside our existing Directors. Closing date for applications 31st December 2019. Informal interviews week commencing 13th January 2020. Advert for Swim England NER Ltd. Directors Job Description for Swim England NER Ltd. Directors Post expires at 9:00am on [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asaner.org.uk/swim-england-north-east-region-ltd-4-additional-directors-vacancies/">Swim England North East Region Ltd. &#8211; 4 additional Directors vacancies</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asaner.org.uk">Swim England North East</a>.</p>
]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Swim England North East Region Ltd. are now recruiting for up to 4 additional Directors to work alongside our existing Directors.<br />
Closing date for applications 31st December 2019.<br />
Informal interviews week commencing 13th January 2020.</p>
<p><a href="https://asaner.org.uk/mdocs-posts/swim-england-ne-region-4-additional-directors-vacancies-nov-2019/">Advert for Swim England NER Ltd. Directors</a><br />
<a href="https://asaner.org.uk/mdocs-posts/swim-england-ne-region-board-members-job-description-nov-2019/">Job Description for Swim England NER Ltd. Directors</a></p>
<p style="font-style: italic;">Post expires at 9:00am on Wednesday January 1st, 2020</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asaner.org.uk/swim-england-north-east-region-ltd-4-additional-directors-vacancies/">Swim England North East Region Ltd. &#8211; 4 additional Directors vacancies</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asaner.org.uk">Swim England North East</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>North East Region Masters Manager</title>
		<link>https://asaner.org.uk/north-east-region-masters-manager/</link>
				<pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2019 10:29:44 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Linda Tjaguns]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Clubs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Masters Swimming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Swimming]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://asaner.org.uk/?p=18860</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<p>Expressions of interest are required for the role of Swim England North East Region Masters Manager. A role description is available at: Swim England North East Region Masters Manager Role Description Please contact the Regional Office if you are interested in the position sending a short statement explaining your experience and why you think you [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asaner.org.uk/north-east-region-masters-manager/">North East Region Masters Manager</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asaner.org.uk">Swim England North East</a>.</p>
]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Expressions of interest are required for the role of Swim England North East Region Masters Manager.</p>
<p>A role description is available at: <a href="http://asaner.org.uk/mdocs-posts/swim-england-north-east-region-masters-manager-job-description/">Swim England North East Region Masters Manager Role Description</a></p>
<p>Please contact the Regional Office if you are interested in the position sending a short statement explaining your experience and why you think you would be suitable for this position:- : linda.tjaguns@swimming.org</p>
<p>Closing date &#8211; Tuesday 31st December 2019</p>
<p style="font-style: italic;">Post expires at 9:27am on Tuesday December 31st, 2019</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asaner.org.uk/north-east-region-masters-manager/">North East Region Masters Manager</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asaner.org.uk">Swim England North East</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>North East Region Swimming Coaches Conference 2020 &#8211; Save the date!</title>
		<link>https://asaner.org.uk/north-east-region-swimming-coaches-conference-2020-save-the-date/</link>
				<pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2019 11:24:07 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[David Parry]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Clubs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Swimming]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Workforce]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://asaner.org.uk/?p=20106</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<p>A Swim England North East Region Swimming Coaches Conference, in partnership with the Swim England Talent Team, will take place on Sunday 15th March 2020 at the Bridge Inn Hotel near Wetherby. The conference will cover various topics including: Optimum Athlete Development Framework The Club Awards programme Developing the characteristics of the future performance potential [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asaner.org.uk/north-east-region-swimming-coaches-conference-2020-save-the-date/">North East Region Swimming Coaches Conference 2020 &#8211; Save the date!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asaner.org.uk">Swim England North East</a>.</p>
]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A Swim England North East Region Swimming Coaches Conference, in partnership with the Swim England Talent Team, will take place on Sunday 15th March 2020 at the Bridge Inn Hotel near Wetherby.</p>
<p>The conference will cover various topics including:</p>
<ul>
<li>Optimum Athlete Development Framework</li>
<li>The Club Awards programme</li>
<li>Developing the characteristics of the future performance potential person</li>
<li>Athlete&#8217;s transitioning through the daily training environment pathway</li>
<li>Coaches Corner to help problem solve</li>
</ul>
<p>The speakers for the day will include experienced coaches, Sports Psychologists, members of the Swim England Talent Team, elite athletes and UK Coaching staff.</p>
<p>Further details, including how to book, will be announced in due course.</p>
<p style="font-style: italic;">Post expires at 11:10am on Sunday March 15th, 2020</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asaner.org.uk/north-east-region-swimming-coaches-conference-2020-save-the-date/">North East Region Swimming Coaches Conference 2020 &#8211; Save the date!</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asaner.org.uk">Swim England North East</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
		<item>
		<title>Regional Swimming Camps 2019</title>
		<link>https://asaner.org.uk/regional-swimming-camps-2019/</link>
				<pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2019 11:10:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[David Parry]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Clubs]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Swimming]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://asaner.org.uk/?p=20103</guid>
				<description><![CDATA[<p>The third and final Swim England North East Region Swimming Camp for 2019 took place at Catterick Leisure Centre on Sunday 24th November 2019. The camps form part of the North East Region Performance Programme and provide an opportunity for swimmers to develop their technical, tactical, physical and psychological skills with swimmers of a similar [&#8230;]</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asaner.org.uk/regional-swimming-camps-2019/">Regional Swimming Camps 2019</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asaner.org.uk">Swim England North East</a>.</p>
]]></description>
								<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>The third and final Swim England North East Region Swimming Camp for 2019 took place at Catterick Leisure Centre on Sunday 24th November 2019.</p>
<p>The camps form part of the North East Region Performance Programme and provide an opportunity for swimmers to develop their technical, tactical, physical and psychological skills with swimmers of a similar age and ability from across the region. The camps also provide an opportunity for swimmers to work with different coaches and to train in different environments and provide a stepping-stone to progress to further camps in the future. The camps engaged with athletes in the 12 year old age group.</p>
<p>Each of the camps was led by Head Coach, Chris Dove with the support and assistance of several Skills Coaches and Team Managers from across the region. Also in attendance to deliver specific sessions at different camps were Strength &amp; Conditioning coaches, a Sports Psychologist and a Nutritionist.</p>
<p>The feedback received is that the camps have been a positive and rewarding experience for all involved.</p>
<p>Any coaches who would like to be considered to be part of future camps as a development opportunity should refer to the Coach Development Pathway document which is available to view at: <a href="https://asaner.org.uk/mdocs-posts/sener-coach-development-pathway-october-2019/">https://asaner.org.uk/mdocs-posts/sener-coach-development-pathway-october-2019/</a></p>
<p>&nbsp;</p>
<p>The post <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asaner.org.uk/regional-swimming-camps-2019/">Regional Swimming Camps 2019</a> appeared first on <a rel="nofollow" href="https://asaner.org.uk">Swim England North East</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
										</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
